

#### DOCTORAL RESEARCHER IN ROBOTICS

University of Freiburg, Georges-Koehler-Allee 80, 79110 Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany

🛮 +49 1578-8744143 | 💌 jannik.zuern@gmail.com | 🏕 jzuern.github.io | 🖸 github.com/jzuern | 🛅 linkedin.com/jannik-zuern | 🎓 Jannik Zürn

# Summary\_

Doctoral robotics researcher at the University of Freiburg, Autonomous Intelligent Systems. I am interested in working on intelligent machines that are able to autonomously operate in complex environments. I like developing algorithms and models from a theoretical angle but I am also passionate about bringing them to life at scale from the software engineering perspective.

## Skills

**Research Interests** Robotics, Perception, Self-Supervised Robot Learning, Computer Vision, Multi-Modal Learning, Scene Understanding

**Programming** Python, PyTorch, ROS, OpenCV, LaTeX, C/C++, TensorFlow **Languages** German (native), English (business fluent), Spanish (elementary)

# **Education**

#### **University of Freiburg, Germany**

Ph.D. Robotics and Artificial Intelligence

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Wolfram Burgard

• Research Focus: Self-Supervised Robot Learning, Perception for Autonomous Robots

#### Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Germany

M.S. THEORETICAL MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (GPA: 3.7/4.0)

• Thesis topic: Neural Networks for Steady-State Fluid Flow Prediction

• Advisors: Dr. S. Suwelack, Dr. Christof Megnin. Grade: 1.0

#### Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Germany

B.S. MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (GPA: 3.1/4.0)

• Thesis topic: Numerical Solution of the Chemical Master Equation

• Advisor: M.Sc. A. Koksharov. Grade: 1.0

# Freiburg, Germany Dec. 2018 - Now

Karlsruhe, Germany

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Karlsruhe, Germany

Oct. 2011 - Aug. 2015

# **Work Experience**

Visiting PhD Student Oxford, England

OXFORD ROBOTICS INSTITUTE, UNIVERSITY OF OXFORD

· Advisor: Prof. Dr. Ingmar Posner

· Research Focus: Self-supervised learning for lane graph estimation in the context of automated driving.

Graduate Research Assistant

Karlsruhe, Germany

RENUMICS GMBH

• Development of machine learning models for steady-state-fluid flow approximation leveraging data-driven computational fluid dynamics.

## **Summer Internship, Robotics Software Engineering**

MAYFIELD ROBOTICS

FEBRUARY 1, 2023

• Development and implementation of a machine learning model for visual place recognition in a companion robot product.

Graduate Research Assistant

Karlsruhe, Germany

FZI RESEARCH CENTER FOR INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

 Development of CUDA Kernels for GPU model inference and model optimization for improved performance with NVIDIA TensorRT

**Graduate Research Assistant** 

INSTITUTE FOR BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, KIT

• Implemented 3D surface reconstruction algorithms for organic tissue from CT images.

• Conducted electrophysiological simulations of human hearts for atrial fibrillation research.

Jun. 2018 – Aug. 2018

Oct. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Redwood City, CA, USA Jul. 2017 – Oct. 2017

> Karlsruhe, Germany Sep. 2016 – Apr. 2018

Karlsruhe, Germany Jan. 2016 – Aug. 2018

JANNIK ZÜRN · RÉSUMÉ 1

## **Summer Internship, Software Engineering**

ANSYS, INC.

 Performed large-scale computational fluid dynamics experiments and parameter studies to optimize internal combustion engine fuel injector models.

## San Diego, CA, USA May 2015 - Sep. 2015

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

INSTITUTE FOR TECHNICAL THERMODYNAMICS, KIT

## Karlsruhe, Germany

Oct. 2014 - Apr. 2015

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

Karlsruhe, Germany Jun. 2013 – Jun. 2014

INSTITUTE FOR APPLIED COMPUTER SCIENCE, KIT

· Implemented computer vision algorithms for automated geometry detection in MATLAB and Simulink.

# **Selected Publications**

Zürn, Jannik, Sebastian Weber, and Wolfram Burgard. "TrackletMapper: Ground Surface Segmentation and Mapping from Traffic Participant Trajectories." Conference for Robot Learning \*CoRL) (2022)

Zürn, Jannik, and Wolfram Burgard. "Self-Supervised Moving Vehicle Detection from Audio-Visual Cues." IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters 7.3 (2022): 7415-7422.

Zürn, Jannik\*, Johan Vertens\*, and Wolfram Burgard. "Lane Graph Estimation for Scene Understanding in Urban Driving." IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters 6.4 (2021): 8615-8622.

Vertens, Johan\*, Jannik Zürn\*, and Wolfram Burgard. "Heatnet: Bridging the day-night domain gap in semantic segmentation with thermal images." 2020 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). IEEE, 2020.

Zürn, Jannik, Wolfram Burgard, and Abhinav Valada. "Self-supervised visual terrain classification from unsupervised acoustic feature learning." IEEE Transactions on Robotics 37.2 (2020): 466-481.

Megnin, C., Moradi, B., Zürn, J., Ossmer, H., Gueltig, M., and Kohl, M. (2020). Shape memory alloy based controllable multi-port microvalve. Microsystem Technologies, 26(3), 793-800.

# Software & Datasets

#### **TrackletMapper**

GROUND SURFACE SEGMENTATION AND MAPPING FROM TRAFFIC PARTICIPANT TRAJECTORIES

http://trackletmapper.cs.uni-freiburg.de

#### AudioVisual Vehicles Dataset

SELF-SUPERVISED MOVING VEHICLE DETECTION FROM AUDIO-VISUAL CUES

http://av-vehicles.cs.uni-freiburg.de

## **Self-Supervised Visual Terrain Classification**

A SELF-SUPERVISED TERRAIN CLASSIFICATION FRAMEWORK USING SOUND AND VISION

http://deepterrain.cs.uni-freiburg.de

#### **Semantic Segmentation of Thermal Images**

BRIDGING THE DAY-NIGHT DOMAIN GAP IN SEMANTIC SEGMENTATION WITH THERMAL IMAGES

http://thermal.cs.uni-freiburg.de

## LaneGraphNet

LANE GRAPH ESTIMATION FOR SCENE UNDERSTANDING IN URBAN DRIVING

http://lanegraph.cs.uni-freiburg.de

# **Reviewing Activites**

- Journals: IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO), IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)
- **Conferences**: IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), IEEE International Conference on Multisensor Fusion and Integration (MFI)

# **Teaching**

- WS 22/23 Seminar Robot Perception for Navigation, Teaching Assistant
  - SS 21 FreiCar: Practical Autonomous Driving, Co-Organizer, Lecturer
- WS 20/21 FreiCar: Practical Autonomous Driving, Co-Organizer, Lecturer
  - SS 19 **Deep Learning Lab**, Teaching Assistant

# **Thesis Supervision**

2021-2022 S. Weber, Self-Supervised Drivable Surface Segmentation for Pedestrian Robots, MS Thesis

2020-2021 **S. Al-Rawi**, Sound Event Localization and Detection, MS Thesis

- 2020 **G. Stief**, Optical Flow based Window Detection, BS Thesis
- 2019 **T. Krautschneider**, Multimodal Object Tracking with Deep Learning, BS Thesis
- 2019 Y. Satyawan, Semantic Segmentation of Curb and Curb Cuts in Street Imagery, BS Thesis